ImageNet is a database of over 10 million hand labeled images,
ImageNet 是一个包含 1000 万以上手动标注图像的数据库
drawn from 1,000 different image categories.
这些图像来自 1,000 个不同的类别
Since 2010, the ImageNet project has held
自 2010 年起 ImageNet 项目一直会举办
the ImageNet Large Scale Visual Recognition Competition,
ImageNet 大规模视觉识别竞赛
an annual competition where teams try to build
来自世界各地的团队会在此年度竞赛中
the best CNN for object recognition and classification.
构建最佳对象识别和分类 CNN
The first breakthrough was in 2012.
在 2012 年出现了第一个突破性的模型
The network called AlexNet,
称之为 AlexNet
was developed by a team at the University of Toronto.
由多伦多大学的团队开发而成
Using the best GPUs available in 2012,
AlexNet 团队使用 2012 年当时最佳的 GPU
the AlexNet team trained the network in about a week.
训练该网络大约一周时间
AlexNet pioneered the use of the ReLU activation function,
AlexNet 开创性地使用了 ReLU 激活函数
and dropout as a technique for avoiding overfitting.
并使用丢弃技巧来避免过拟合
In 2014, two different groups nearly tied in the ImageNet competition.
在 2014 年 有两个团队几乎在 ImageNet 竞赛中打成平手
One of those networks was called VGGNet,
其中一个网络叫做 VGGNet
often referred to as just VGG,
通常简称为 VGG
and it came from the Visual Geometry Group at Oxford University.
它由牛津大学的视觉几何团队开发而成
VGG has two versions termed VGG16,
VGG 有 VGG 16 和 VGG 19 这两个版本
and VGG 19, with 16 and 19 total layers respectively.
分别共有 16 个和 19 个层级
Both versions have a simple and elegant architecture,
二者都结构简单出彩
which is just a long sequence of three by three convolutions,
由一系列 3x3 卷积层组成
broken up by two by two pooling layers,
中间夹杂着 2x2 池化层
and finished with three fully-connected layers.
最后是 3 个全连接层
VGG pioneered the exclusive use of small three by three convolution windows,
VGG 率先独家使用很小的 3x3 卷积窗口
to contrast AlexNets much larger 11 by 11 windows.
而 AlexNet 的卷积窗口大得多 大小为 11x11
In 2015, the ImageNet winner was a network from Microsoft Research called ResNet.
在 2015 年 ImageNet 获胜者是微软研究院开发的网络 叫做 ResNet
ResNet is like VGG and not the same structure is repeated again and again,
ResNet 和 VGG 有点像 不会一直重复相同的结构
for layer after layer.
一层又一层
Also like VGG, ResNet has different versions that vary in their number of layers.
和 VGG 一样 ResNet 也有很多不同的版本 相互之间的层级数量不同
The largest having a groundbreaking 152 layers.
最大版本具有突破性的 152 层
Previous researchers tried to make their CNNs this deep,
之前的研究员也尝试使 CNN 达到这个深度
but they ran into a problem where as they were adding layers,
但是他们遇到了问题 当他们添加更多层级时
performance increased up to a point,
性能增加到某个点后
after which performance quickly declined.
就开始快速下降
This is partially due to what's known as the vanishing gradient's problem,
部分原因是梯度消失问题造成的
which arises when we go to train the network through backpropagation.
当我们通过反向传播训练网络时 就可能会遇到此问题
The main idea is that the gradient signal has to be pushed through the entire network.
主要原理是梯度信号必须散布到整个网络中
The deeper the network becomes,
网络越深
the more likely that the signal gets weakened before it gets where it needs to go.
信号在达到目的地之前就越有可能变弱
The ResNet team added connections to their very deep CNN that skip layers.
ResNet 团队在很深的 CNN 中添加了跳过层级的连接
So, the gradient signal has a shorter route to travel.
所以梯度信号的传播路径变短了
ResNet achieves superhuman performance in classifying images in the ImageNet database.
ResNet 在分类 ImageNet 数据库中的图像方面取得了惊人的效果